

# back-end developer

<u>mcicek@outlook.com</u> +905300370255 linkedin.com/in/mustafacicek github.com/mstfcck

### **ABOUT**

<u>Currently</u>, has 10 years of experience. Using the latest technologies develops cloud-based projects. The focus is on infrastructure development of projects, creating and improving architectural designs, code review, supporting and mentoring the team, etc.

The main area of expertise is back-end development using "dotNET". Also have many experiences on 3rd party tools, frameworks, libraries and technologies.

A strict follower of software architectures, approaches, best practices, and software design patterns and principles. Such as SOLID, DRY, KISS, YAGNI, Design Patterns, Domain-Driven Design, CQRS, Event Sourcing, Microservices, etc.

<u>In the past</u>, had experience in many projects with complex business processes. He took part in all end-to-end processes of the projects he worked on in the early stages of his experience. Such as business analysis, technical analysis, application design, development, testing, etc.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Lead .NET Developer**

adesso Turkey / July 2020 - Present

As a Lead Developer my principal responsibilities:

- Mentoring and advised the development team on technical issues and standards, as well as the architectural approach towards pieces of work.
- Line management.
- Evaluate software designs and architectures of other developers.
- Review and provide quality control for technology delivery teams (design/code review).
- Documentation of technical design and analysis work.
- Documentation of code, patterns, and practices.
- Implementation of solutions based on best practices.
- Design of applications based on re-use and scalability.
- Developing "Proof of Concept" projects and overarching technical pieces to help drive innovation and allow the feature teams to focus on delivering the business asks.
- Job interviewing with candidates.

# **Senior Software Developer**

adesso Turkey / December 2019 - Present

### Non-technical Responsibilities

- Technical project management.
- Estimating the efforts of other employees.
- Organizing tasks and dates.
- Identifying priorities and designing workflows.
- Identifying the risks and problems in the project and providing solutions accordingly.
- Giving feedback to the people in the team within the scope of the project.
- Supporting software architects and project managers in decision-making.

- Supporting and motivating team members on technical issues.
- To make appropriate distribution of tasks to team members.
- Finding solutions to the problems that occur in the communication of the team.

### **Technical Responsibilities**

- Determination and development of flow in accordance with business rules.
- Investigating appropriate practices that can be a solution to changing needs during the development process of the project and applying them in the project.
- Developing the project by positioning the software components correctly.
- Determining practices and disciplines together with the team so that the team can speak the same language about development.
- To follow up and implement code quality standards.
- Documentation of code, pattern, and practices.
- Code review.

### Software Languages, Libraries, and Frameworks & Technologies & Tools

- C#, .NET Core 2.x/3.x, ASP.NET Core 2.x/3.x
- SQL Server, MongoDB
- Dapper, MediatR, AutoMapper, FluentValidation, Masstransit, IdentityServer4, Ocelot (API Gateway), NEST, Refit, Serilog, Swashbuckle (Swagger),
- ElasticSearch, Kibana, RabbitMQ, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Azure (Blob Storage, AKS, SQL Managed Instances)

#### Architectures & Patterns and Practices

- Microservices, Event Sourcing, RESTful API, Back-end for Front-end, Dependency Injection, Richardson Maturity Model

#### Project Management Tools & Methodologies

- Bitbucket, Jira, Confluence, Microsoft Teams, Agile/Scrum

# **R&D Software Developer**

DataMarket / December 2018 – December 2019

Responsible for technical analysis and development of the company's R&D projects.

### Compass Connected and Smart, connectedandsmart.com

Helps you to make your products be connected all the time, collect critical machine telemetry data and log machine performance.

Provides an intuitive web interface to remotely monitor, analyze and compare your product performance.

Sends your support team relevant messages to inform them about the support requirements of your customers.

Connects your support team remotely to your products over secure VPN connections and make them fix problems easily and fast.

Enables you to give access to these valuable machine telemetry information to your customers as well. Your customer operation and support teams will monitor and analyze your products over the web interface. They can subscribe to alert and warnings messages. They can use our API interface to integrate machine data into MES and ERP platforms.

Technology Stack: .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework Core, Dapper, Azure (WebApps, Functions, Stream Analytics, CosmosDb, Blob Storage, SQL Server, IoT Hub, KeyVault, Application Insights, DevOps (CI/CD)), GitHub

### NFC Door Lock (RaspberryPi)

Can be integrated with all types of electronic door locks.

Provides a digital interface to users with a screen for door locks.

Door authorizations can be managed by integrating your existing software through the API provided by the application software.

Many NFC supported card types can be defined in the system (such as NFC Sticker or Card, Public Transport Card).

Can work offline.

Technology Stack: .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, SignalR, Dapper, NLog, Raspberry Pi, Electron, NodeJS, GitHub

# **Back-End Developer**

Bilgetech / April 9 – November 30, 2018

Responsible for technical analysis and development of back-end services for mobile & web applications and integrations.

### Araç İste (Request a Car), bilgetech.com.tr/projects/arac-iste

Araç İste is an intranet mobile application that has developed by Bilgetech for the companies of Koc Holding.

Features and Modules: Vehicle Demand from Mobile Applications, Live Vehicle Monitoring On Map, Invoicing, Different Management Panel for Suppliers and Customers.

### Aygaz Mobile App, bilgetech.com.tr/projects/aygaz-mobile-app

Features and Modules: General and special campaigns and tracking current purchase and point status in the campaigns you participate in. Nearest Aygaz and Mogaz Autogas Stations. Travel Route Calculation, Paro points account and review your score movements. Facebook chatbot.

#### Kolektif House Coworking Management, koplanet.kolektifhouse.co

Features and Modules: Management of Companies and Members. Meeting Room Reservation & Pricing. Access Management of Members to the Doors, Meeting Rooms, WiFi, etc. Integrations with 3rd Party Services (such as WiFi, Salto Door Locks, etc.)

#### Common Stack:

Common Architecture & Coding Practices: 3-Tier Architecture (Presentation, Application, Data), Unit Of Work, Repository, Code First (Entity Framework Core), RESTful Services

Common Technology Stack: .NET Core, .NET Framework, C#, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET Web API, Entity Framework Core, Entity Framework, Dapper, MSSQL, NLog, Swagger, OAuth2, OpenId Connect, JWT, Google Maps API, OpenIddict, Hangfire, KendoUI, VSTS (Azure DevOps), Git

# **Back-End Developer**

B2C Direct / October 2017 – April 2018

Responsible for technical analysis and development of back-end services for web applications and integrations.

#### GoB2C, gob2c.com

GoB2C is a cloud-based and intelligent logistics management service offered to all companies who want to export e-commerce.

Technology Stack: .NET Framework, C#, ASP.NET Web API, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, Dapper, Windows Services, MSSQL, NLog, Quartz, FluentValidation, Redis, RabbitMQ, Swagger, Autofac, VSTS

# **Software Developer**

Tekfen Engineering / June 2016 – August 2017

Responsible for business & technical analysis and development of the company's internal projects and integrations.

- Project Resource Planning Application

- Human Resources Application
- Desktop Applications and Integrations with the software used in the company

Technology Stack: .NET Framework, C#, ASP.NET Web API, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, Dapper, WCF Services, MSSQL, Java Spring Boot, Hibernate, JavaScript (JQuery, Angular 1.x), KendoUI (Angular), log4net, HangFire, Redis, YouTrack, TeamCity, Unit Tests

# **Software Developer**

Aksis Bilgisayar / July 2015 – May 2016

Responsible for business & technical analysis and development of the company's internal projects and integrations.

#### **DOX Electronic Document Management System**

(Turkish: Elektronik Belge Yönetim Sistemi (EBYS))

DOX is a certified (TSE: TS13298:2015) product by the Turkish Standards Institute. DOX provides management of incoming and outgoing documents between public institutions.

Features and Modules: AD Authentication, Registered Electronic Mail, Electronic Signature, Document Scanning and OCR (Optical Character Recognition), Archiving and Indexing, etc.

Architecture & Coding Practices: 3-Tier Architecture (Presentation, Application, Data), Unit Of Work, Repository, Code First (Entity Framework)

Technology Stack: .NET Framework, C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, WCF Services, MSSQL, JavaScript (JQuery, Handlebars), HangFire, iTextSharp, log4net, ElasticSearch, Tesseract (OCR)

#### Workflow

Workflow is a Web API module that works with DOX. This module provides a workflow infrastructure for managing document approval processes.

Architecture & Coding Practices: Unit Of Work, Repository, Code First (Entity Framework)

Technology Stack: .NET Framework, C#, ASP.NET Web API, Entity Framework, MSSQL, log4net

# **Analyst Developer**

Nuevo Softwarehouse / July 2014 – July 2015

Responsible for technical analysis and development of the projects and integrations.

B/S/H Turkey is the greatest home appliances company in Turkey with foreign investments that hosts with brands like Bosch, Siemens, Gaggenau, and Profilo within our country.

#### B/S/H Dealer Communication Portal (Turkish: Bayi İletişim Portalı (BİP))

BİP is a dealer communication portal that hosts many modules, such as the B2B infrastructure, as well as the order, offer, survey, and email modules for those brands.

Technology Stack: .NET Framework 3.5, C#, ASP.NET WebForms, MSSQL, LLBLGen, ADO.NET, Ajax Control Toolkit, Windows Services, iTextSharp, Quartz, Highcharts, JQuery, Ajax, Google Maps API

### B/S/H Brand Communication Portal (Turkish: Marka İletişim Portalı (MİP))

MİP is a web application that provides communication between brands.

#### B/S/H Dealer To Consumer

Technology Stack: .NET Framework, C#, ASP.NET MVC 4, MSSQL, Entity Framework, Castle Windsor

Dertour is one of the leading German tourism enterprises. Dertour Hotel Directory

Hotel Directory is a web application that provides hotels from different countries.

Technology Stack: .NET Framework, C#, ASP.NET MVC 4, MSSQL, Entity Framework, Autofac

### Nuevo Softwarehouse, http://www.nuevo.com.tr

Our company's website has a CMS infrastructure.

### Oyak Yatırım FX Web Site, http://www.oyakyatirimfx.com

Oyak Yatırım FX's website that has a CMS infrastructure.

### Medicana Hospital Mobil Web Site

Medicana Hospital's mobile website has a CMS infrastructure.

## **Database Developer**

Tekfen Engineering / July 2011 – June 2014

### IBM FileNet P8 Platform and IBM Content Navigator

Responsible for administration (authorization management, content & archive management, etc.) of products.

### **IBM Business Process Manager**

Responsible for workflow design, develop and maintenance for projects.

## Application Development (Internal)

"TimeSheet" is a desktop application used to keep track of employees' working time.

"Planning" is a desktop application that provides monthly planning of projects.

#### Reporting

Reporting with InfoMaker, Crystal Report of projects from databases (MSSQL, Sybase).

Technology Stack: Visual Basic 6.0, C#, Windows Services, WCF, MSSQL, Sybase, InfoMaker, Crystal Report

### **EDUCATION**

## **Computer Programming**

September 2009 – May 2011

Associate's Degree, Sakarya University

# **Database Programming**

September 2005 – June 2009

High School, Technical High School

### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATIONS**

Married, Live in İstanbul/Turkey